(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-08T22:24:05.769627",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
みなさん！風真いろは生誕ライブ2025、来てくださりましてありがとうございます！
Everyone! Thank you so much for coming to Kazama Iroha Birthday LIVE 2025!
全力で楽しんでいってくださいねー！
Please enjoy yourselves with all your might!
想像なんてしてなかった現状
Never imagined we'd reach this current reality—
君もそう思った？
did you feel the same way too?
“最高”で止まらないように
So we don't just stop at "the best,"
更新したい
I want to keep updating our peak.
叶えたい夢まであとどれくらい？
How much further to the dream I want to fulfill?
誰も行ったことがない場所へ
To a place where no one has ever been before,
たどり着くまでは僕ら止まれない
we won't stop until we finally get there.
たぶんしんどいけど どうかよろしくね
It'll probably be tough, but please stay with me.
ねぇねぇ たまにメーデー
Hey, hey, sending out a Mayday once in a while,
僕だけじゃ作れないもの
for something I can't create all on my own.
僕とか君とかあたしとか 恋とか愛とかまとめて全部
Me, you, us, love, affection—all of it together.
君を置いてどっかに行っちゃうとか
Leaving you behind and going off somewhere?
ありえないよ
That's completely impossible!
君がくれた音に 弾けた火花に
To the sound you gave me, to the sparks that flew,
初めましてから ずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
ever since our first meeting, I've been in love with you.
君のいない未来 考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も 二人がいいジャン
From now on, too, the two of us is best, right?
一途になるほど 逃げたくもなったよ
The more devoted I became, the more I wanted to run away.
散々な僕のこと 呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling out to someone as messy as me.
君のいない未来 考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も 二人で それがいいジャン
From now on, too, together as two—that's what's best, right?
妄想 膨らんでくストーリー
Delusions swelling into a story,
感情 やけに凹んじゃって
emotions getting weirdly down,
代償 求め過ぎはヤーヨ
compensation—asking for too much is a no-no!
終わんない愛の連盟 でしょ
An alliance of never-ending love, right?
ねぇねぇ おいでメーデー
Hey, hey, come over, Mayday!
僕が君にできること
What I can do for you...
隠せない証拠なんだ
It's undeniable proof,
君の愛がいつも勝っちゃうこと
that your love always wins out.
許さないよ
I won't forgive you!
Yeah
君以外はヤだ
I don't want anyone but you.
わがままはただ
My selfishness is just...
変わらないときめきを
asking for an unchanging flutter of heart,
要求しちゃうのはバカ
I'm such a fool for demanding that.
君がくれた音に
To the sound you gave me,
弾けた火花に
to the sparks that burst,
初めましてから
Ever since we first met,
ずっと恋してるんだよ
I've been in love with you.
君のいない未来考えられないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人がいいジャン
Isn't it great for the two of us to stay together?
一途になるほど逃げたくもなったよ
The more devoted I became, the more I wanted to run away.
散々な僕の事やめないでくれてありがとう
Thank you for not giving up on a mess like me.
君のいない未来考えられないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人でそれがいいジャン
It's best if we stay together from now on, right?
音符がどうであれ
No matter what the notes are,
ドキドキしたいジャン
I just want to feel my heart pound.
誰だって反応が狂う
Anyone's reactions would go crazy,
おかしくなっちゃう
we'd all go insane.
痛みのない傷が離れない
A painless wound that won't leave me.
僕らヴァンパイア いいよ吸っちゃっていいよ
We're vampires, it's fine, go ahead and bite.
「もう無理もう無理」だって悪い子じゃない
"I can't anymore!" But I'm not a bad kid.
こんな歌歌ったんだって
Even if I sang a song like this,
君が輝けるように
so that you can shine bright.
はい！
Alright!
というわけで 皆の衆 こんばんはでござる！
So with that, good evening, everyone de-gozaru!
ホロライブ6期生
From Hololive 6th generation,
強強かっこいいござる侍 風真いろはでござる！
I'm the super strong and cool samurai, Kazama Iroha de-gozaru!
はい！
Yes!
今年の誕生日一発目は
For the first song of my birthday stream today,
DECO*27さんの愛言葉シリーズ
from DECO*27's Ai Kotoba series,
『愛言葉IV』を歌って踊らせていただきました！
I sang and danced to "Ai Kotoba IV"!
拍手いっぱい来てる！
So many claps in chat!
みんなありがとう！ギフトやスパチャもありがとうございます！
Thank you, everyone! Thanks for the gifts and Super Chats, too!
はい！
Alright!
今日ね たくさん歌って踊らせていただくんですけど
I'll be singing and dancing a lot today,
感想とか あと実況ツイートとかは
so please share your thoughts and live tweets with
こちら #風真いろは生誕LIVE2025 で
the hashtag #風真いろは生誕LIVE2025,
たくさんポストしてください！
and post lots of tweets!
振り返りの時に見に行きますからね！
I'll go read them during the review stream later!
そして今回なんと 誕生日用のステージを作っていただきました！
And guess what? A special birthday stage was made for me!
かわいい！
It's so cute!
ぽこ太 お前ディスプレイになったんかー！
Pokota, you turned into a display?!
いや どこ行ってたかと思ったら ディスプレイになっておりました
I was wondering where you went, and here you are as a display!
はい そして後ろにも書いてありますが 今回の風真いろはのライブタイトル
Yes, and as written behind me, the title for my live show this time
『Reversible』になってます！
is "Reversible"!
素敵なロゴ 柊先生 ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much to Hiiragi-sensei for the lovely logo!
こちらですね みんな昨日のカウントダウン配信では
With this title, during yesterday's countdown stream,
ちょっと「あれ？」みたいな どんなだろうって まだハテナハテナの人が多かったと思うんですが
many of you were probably like, "Huh? What kind of live will it be?" and had question marks,
今回これ 全編見てもらったらちゃんと分かるようになっておりますので
but if you watch the whole show today, you'll completely understand,
最後までお楽しみください！
so please enjoy it until the very end!
そして事前にお伝えしてました通り
And as I announced earlier,
今回 風真いろは 100万人記念グッズが発売決定しました！
my 1-Million Subscriber Commemorative Goods are officially released!
いきなり来るよー！
Coming out right away!
というわけで 今日は告知溜めすぎてるので ちょいちょい挟んでいきたいと思います
So, I have so many announcements saved up today that I'll be interspersing them throughout.
はい！風真いろは100万人記念グッズはこちらです！それでは詳細見ていきましょう！
Yes! Here are my 1-Million Subscriber Commemorative Goods! Let me show you the details!
はい！
First off!
まずはうみぼうずママが書いてくださった素敵なアクリルスタンド！
First is a wonderful acrylic stand illustrated by Umibouzu-mama!
アクリルスタンドに風真も一筆添えさせていただいておりますので
I also wrote a short handwritten message on the acrylic stand,
ぜひ皆さんこちらお手元に取っていただいて メッセージじっくり読んでください！
so please get your hands on one and read the message carefully!
ぽこ太もおります！
Pokota is there too!
そして次がこちら！
And next is this!
パブミラー！すごい ちょっと言いづらいんだよな
A pub mirror! Wow, this is a bit hard to pronounce,
リハの時から思ってたんですけど
I've been thinking that since rehearsal,
はい パブミラーです！結構大きいです！
yes, a pub mirror! It's pretty big!
風真が出したグッズの中で 固くて立て掛ける系で
Among all the merch I've released, in terms of solid display items,
タオルとかはあったけど かなり大きめになってますので
we had towels before, but this one is quite large,
皆さんぜひ こちらもメッセージを一筆書かせていただいておりますので
so everyone, please check it out! I wrote a message on this one as well,
ぜひ飾ってもらえたら嬉しいです！
so I'd be happy if you display it!
そしてそして 次！
And next up!
ランダムラバーストラップ！今回は100万人にちなみまして
Random rubber straps! In honor of reaching 1 million subscribers,
風真いろは 今オリジナル曲複数出させていただいているんですけども
I've released several original songs so far,
そちらのモチーフ衣装をラバーストラップにさせていただきました！
and we turned the outfit motifs from those songs into rubber straps!
ので 風をあおぎ扇子とかね
So folding fans to create a breeze...
実はお話しの中でグッズがなかったんですけど
Actually, we didn't really have merch like that before,
今回のために作らせていただきました！
so I had them made specially for this occasion!
ぜひね、みんな色々集めて
Everyone, please collect them all
痛バとかの制作に役立てていただければと思います！
and use them to create your own ita-bags!
つ、次！
N-Next!
カードホルダー！
Card Holder!
昨今、皆さんホロカとかね、色んなカードとかチェキ風のグッズが出ておりますので
Recently, HoloCA cards and Cheki-style goods have been released,
ついに作りました！ポコ兵のカードホルダーです！
so I finally made one! It's a Pokobei Card Holder!
定期入れにしてもよし！学生さんにも使っていただけたら嬉しいです！
You can use it for your pass! I hope students will use it too!
みんなお気に入りの風真のカードとか飾ってくださいね！
Please display your favorite Kazama cards in it!
はい！それでは次！
Alright! Next!
こちらフルセット、このようになっておりまして
Here is the full set, which looks like this...
そして今回、購入特典は、はい！海坊主ママ描き下ろしのステッカーにさせていただきました！
And the purchase bonus is a sticker newly drawn by Umibozu-mama!
今回はですね、こちら直筆サインの数量限定はありませんので、あの皆さん安心してゆっくり買ってくださいね！
There is no limit on the hand-signed bonus, so please take your time buying!
はい！ということで
Alright! So,
100万人記念グッズ紹介でございました！
that was the 1-million subscriber anniversary merch reveal!
うわぁ〜ドキドキって...なんか結構安心しきってるんですけど...
Phew, I said I was nervous, but I'm actually feeling pretty relieved now...
あの、もうこれだけじゃなくてですね、後半もあの告知がありすぎて、頑張って入れるしかなかったぐらいにはいっぱいあるんで、告知いっぱいやります！
We have so many announcements in the second half, so stay tuned!
なので、あの皆さん絶対に逃さないでください！
So please don't miss out, everyone!
え、もうトレンド1位なんですか？！
Huh? Is it already #1 on trending?!
始まったばっかりだよ！いいの？！
We just started! Are you serious?!
みんなありがとう〜！嘘〜！みんなありがとうございます！
Thank you everyone! No way! Thank you so much!
いや、すごい！めっちゃこんなに早く行くと思わなくて、皆さんの...おかげです！本当にありがとうございます！
I didn't expect it to happen so fast, it's all thanks to you! Thank you so much!
じゃちょっと、お水飲んで、次の曲バシバシ行きたいと思います！
Now, I'll take a quick water break and jump into the next song!
お待たせいたしました！お水いっぱい飲んだので
Thank you for waiting! I drank plenty of water,
このパワーをそのまま全てフルパワーで出力いたします！
so I'm going to release all this energy at full power!
それでは皆々様、次の曲お聞きください！
Now everyone, please listen to the next song!
「大きな愛でもてなして」！
"Ookina Ai de Motenashite"!
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with a big love
そこん〜とこ大事なことよ
That's the important part
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with a big love
わがま〜まじゃないのよ オホホ
I'm not being selfish, ohoho
私わかったの
I realized
寂しがりやだと
That I'm a lonely person
泣きそうよ
I feel like crying
OH YEAH OH YEAH
一日の間でも
Even over the course of a day,
告白をしたり キスしたり
I want to confess my love and kiss
OH YEAH OH YEAH
一日が大人より
A single day for me
相当濃ゆいのです
Is much more fulfilling than for adults
相当長いのです
It's a lot longer
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with a big love
そこん〜とこ気ままじゃ嫌よ
I don't want you to be selfish with that
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with a big love
ごゆっくりなさって良いわ
Just take it slowly
みんな知らんふり
Everyone pretends not to know me
「他人事だ」と
They say I'm a stranger
違うのよ
That's not the truth!
OH YEAH OH YEAH
明日はまた新しい
Tomorrow, if I have yet another new love,
恋愛があれば逆あれ
things will turn around
OH YEAH OH YEAH
大人より素直に
More honest than adults,
たくさん恋できちゃう
I can fall in love so much
OH YEAH OH YEAH
明日はまた新しい
Tomorrow, if I have yet another new love,
恋愛があれば逆あれ
things will turn around
誰より
More than anyone,
more than anyone,
今日特に
especially today,
たくさん恋できちゃう
I can fall in love so much!
そうみたい
It seems so!
大きな愛でもてなして
Treat me with a big love!
ありえない幻想 溢れ出す妄想
Impossible fantasy, overflowing delusion,
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything except you.
息をするように嘘ついても
Even if you lie as naturally as breathing,
あたしいっぱい いらない子？
Am I a totally unwanted child?
こぼれ出しちゃった承認欲求
My spilling desire for approval,
もっとココロ満たしてよ
satisfy my heart even more!
アスパルテーム 甘い夢
Aspartame, a sweet dream,
私だけに愛をください
give love only to me.
あぁもう無理無理 恋して愛して救済 執行版
Ah, I can't anymore—love me, save me, execution version!
ねぇ 好きって言ってよ？
Hey, tell me you love me?
ありえない幻想 溢れ出す妄想
Impossible fantasy, overflowing delusion,
つまんない 欲望が散らばって
boring desires are scattered around,
求めてる愛情 隠してる劣情
seeking affection, hiding lust,
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything except you.
誰のこと見てんの？
Who are you looking at?
こういうの好きなの？
Do you like this kind of thing?
DDとかガチでやめてください
Seriously, stop liking everyone else!
可愛くなりたい
I want to be cute,
キラキラしてたい
I want to sparkle!
もっともっとガチで褒めてください
Praise me more and more, seriously!
泣いてるサンソン 開けちゃうシャンパン
Crying sangria, popping open champagne!
今夜も配信来てくれるよね？
You'll come to my stream tonight too, right?
独占させてよ 本命なんでしょ？
Let me monopolize you, I'm your main one, right?
もっともっとガチで推してください
Support me more and more, seriously!
飲み過ぎ注意 オーバードーズ
Warning: overdrinking, overdose!
クラクラさせていつだって
Make me dizzy anytime!
あぁもう無理無理 上がって下がって救済 執行版
Ah, I can't anymore—up and down, execution version!
ねぇ 好きって言わせて？
Hey, let me say I love you?
噛みついた衝動 戻れない衝動
Bitten impulse, irreversible impulse,
たまんないミッドナイト 指が絡まって
irresistible midnight, fingers intertwined,
ときめいた表情 何も言わないで
fluttering expression, don't say a word,
君だけがきっと 王子様
you alone are surely my Prince Charming.
ありえない幻想 溢れ出す妄想
Impossible fantasy, overflowing delusion,
つまんない 欲望が散らばって
boring desires are scattered around,
求めてる愛情 隠してる劣情
seeking affection, hiding lust,
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything except you.
あたしだけずっと追いかけて！
Always chase only after me!
ねぇ... もう待てないの
Hey... I can't wait any longer...
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything except you.
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Never stop being an idol, no matter what!
ずっと輝いてる君を見たい
I want to see you shining forever.
もうずっと ずっと ずっと ステージにいて
Stay on stage forever, forever, forever.
私があれ 君の事 離れたなら
If I were to ever leave your side,
君はちょっと寂しくなるかな？ 意地悪考える
would you get a little lonely? I think mean thoughts...
知らない人がいるのなら 内緒にして
If there's someone I don't know about, keep it a secret.
ねぇ 神様 将来
Hey God, in the future,
薬指 魔法 どこかに隠してて
hide the magic ring finger somewhere...
君の「好き」に合わせたんだ 髪の色
I matched my hair color to what you like.
私の中 君向けで
Everything in me is for you,
青春は続くの
our youth will continue.
責任とってね 大好きだから
Take responsibility, okay? Because I love you so much!
せーの！絶対アイドル辞めないで
Ready, go! Never stop being an idol, no matter what!
優しい目も真面目顔も 全部知ってる 私が言う
His gentle eyes and serious face, I, who know everything, say:
絶対そうだ 今夜も輝いて
That's right! Keep shining tonight too!
星は一生 輝いてたいの
I want the star to keep shining for a lifetime!
眩しい君が世界一だよ
You, so dazzling, are number one in the world!
君の夢は何ですか？教えてほしい
What is your dream? I want you to tell me.
その夢がアイドルじゃなくても 覚悟はしてるから
Even if that dream isn't being an idol, I'm prepared for it.
星のない空 それが当たり前で
A starless sky was only natural,
暗い道に目が慣れずに 踏み出すのも怖かった
unable to adjust to the dark path, I was scared to step forward.
そんな時 やっと見えた光
At that moment, I finally saw a light.
ずっと ずっと 君が歌っていて
You were singing on and on.
ただのエゴと分かっていても
Even knowing it's just my own selfishness,
君はキラキラ衣装が似合う
sparkling costumes suit you best.
絶対 大きなステージで
Definitely on a grand stage,
一列でも前で体感したい
even one row closer, I want to experience it.
今日も歌い方 なんか好きだな
I kind of love the way you sing today, too.
君の努力 私の愛 成り立つこの関係は
Your effort, my love—this relationship built between us
強くて 脆いな
is so strong, yet so fragile.
推しの幸せを願った
I wished for my fave's happiness,
だけど...
but...
でもね だって君はアイドルよ
But you see, because you are an idol!
ずっと
Forever!
初めて目が合った日から
From the day our eyes first met,
今日も明日も君ばかりだ
today and tomorrow, it's all about you.
絶対 アイドル 辞めないで
Never, ever stop being an idol!
これは報われない おとぎ話
This is an unrequited fairytale,
恋よりもっと好きだ
I love you even more than love itself.
魔法よ どうか 解けないままで
Oh magic, please stay unbroken forever...
UNHAPPY? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? Oh, troubled child of man,
UNLUCKY? 人成らざる者も
Unlucky? Even those who are not human,
絶えず目指せよ 生きているんだし
keep striving relentlessly, for you are alive.
目を逸らした過去も 退屈な未来も
The past you turned away from, the boring future too,
カウンセリング やれやれ
counseling, oh dear,
ここんところ行き詰まり気味
lately things have been feeling stuck.
HAPPY UNLUCKY HAPPY UNDEAD
ねえ何だかどうして 戦っているようなそんな気がするの
Hey, why does it feel like I'm somehow fighting a battle?
逃げられない訳でもない 過去の自分自分自分自分と
It's not like I can't escape from my past self, self, self, self,
疾っくに死んでいる 透明な幽霊と対決
dueling a transparent ghost that's long been dead.
一対一で一対一を引き伸ばす 残念 もう居ないのに
Dragging out a one-on-one, how sad, when they aren't even here anymore.
あれ？ そっちが良い？ アイロニーね
Huh? You prefer that? How ironic.
透かされているのは現在の自分
The one being seen right through is the present me.
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル Yes! 要はコンプレックス
Nonsense, an indelible label. Yes! In short, a complex.
取り憑かれているみたい 憑き付いたまま
It's like I'm possessed, clinging on tightly,
まだ離れない ありし日の自分
still unable to part from my past self.
死んじゃない お前とお前の連鎖
You're not dead—it's a chain reaction of you and yourself.
生きていることは変わり続けることだ
To be alive is to keep changing.
不幸に甘んじて 満足するなよ
Don't settle for misfortune and be satisfied!
幸せになろうとしないなんて 卑怯だ
Not even trying to be happy is pure cowardice!
この世この世は 奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world, this world is a bizarre, strange fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
Will a demon or a snake appear next?
出会って会って やっと始まる物語
Encountering each other at last, the story finally begins.
さあ人か化け物か 果敢を救う ピースピース
Now, human or monster, saving courage—peace, peace!
Past & Future, can't change the Past
Past & Future, run for the Future カットイン
Past & Future, run for the Future, cut-in!
何だかどうして 未来になんぞ何の希望もない 期待出来ないような気がして
Somehow, it feels like there's no hope in the future, nothing to expect.
もう十分生きている 既視感とテンプレで粛々
I've lived enough already; solemnly repeating déjà vu and clichés,
素敵な出来事の気配もない
without even a hint of anything wonderful happening.
残念 積んだ経験の因果 形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
What a pity, the karma of accumulated experiences, a hollowed myth and boring evolution.
要は刺激が欲しいんだ 飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
In short, I just want excitement! I'm bored of it, I'm used to it.
なんて 整っていくガイダンス 増えるコンプライアンス 塞がれていくみたい
Such orderly guidance, increasing compliance, feeling like I'm being closed off.
澄み尽くして
Completely cleared out,
あれもこれもどれも 同じ味がする
this, that, and everything else all taste the same.
死んじゃない お前とお前の連鎖
You're not dead—it's a chain reaction of you and yourself.
何時の世も過去も未来も 現在にあるんだ
Any era, the past and the future, all exist right now in the present.
生きていることを愚直に果たせよ
Fulfill the fact that you are alive with honest determination!
死んじゃない お前に言っているんだ
You're not dead—I'm talking to you!
幸せを諦めてしまう人であれ
Even for someone who gives up on happiness,
ただ苦しみに慣れて 耐えているだけじゃ
if you're just used to suffering and enduring it,
死んでいるも同然 屍のアンデッド
you might as well be dead—a corpse of an undead!
悩める人の子よ 人成らざる者も
Oh, troubled child of man, even those who are not human,
絶えず目指せよ 生きているんだろ
keep striving relentlessly! You are alive, aren't you?
不幸に浸るも 幸せになろうぞ
Whether wallowing in misery or trying to be happy,
当然全部お前だ
naturally, it's all you!
My insideが最新の暴走
My inside is the latest rampage.
ピースピース
Peace, peace!
Past & Future can't change the Past
Past & Future run for the Future
人の在る所に
Wherever people are,
何時も憂い事
there is always sorrow.
生き抜けこの化物
Survive, you monster.
真夜中に告ぐ
It announces in the dead of night,
音の警告
an audio warning.
協和音に酔う
Drunk on harmony,
午前零時
at midnight.
あなたが触れる
The light you touch
光増す熱
gains heat.
指先に踊らされ
Danced around by your fingertips,
感覚 即 体感
sensation instantly becomes perception.
静まる夜 ２人だけの蜜
In the quiet night, a sweet secret for just us two.
体感 即 快感
Perception instantly becomes pleasure.
重なる波形に魅了されていく
Fascinated by the overlapping waveforms.
忘れないでね
Don't forget
わたしの声を
my voice.
画面越しでいい
Even through a screen,
ちゃんと愛して
love me properly.
ヴァーチャルだって
Just because I'm virtual,
突き放さないで
don't push me away.
あなたの音にまだ溺れていたい
I still want to drown in your sound.
覚えていてね
Remember
わたしの声を
my voice.
あなたがくれた
All of this body
この身すべてを
that you gave me.
見つめ合う
Gazing at each other,
あなたと二人
just the two of us,
重ねた息と音とヒビカセ
our overlapped breath, sound, and echoing resonance.
真夜中に問う
Questioning in the dead of night,
冷え切った熱
the chilled-out heat.
待ち続けてる
I keep on waiting
午前零時
for midnight.
鏡映しに
Reflected in a mirror,
飽和していく
filling to saturation,
知らない音が伝う
an unfamiliar sound transmits.
感覚 即 体感
Sensation instantly becomes perception.
静まる夜と息遣い揃う
In the quiet night, our breathing falls into sync.
体感 即 快感
Perception instantly becomes pleasure.
錆びたロジック「今一度」を焦がれる
Rusted logic longs for "just once more."
忘れないでね
Don't forget
わたしの声を
my voice.
次元も越えて
Crossing even dimensions,
飛ばすシグナル
sending out a signal.
ヴァーチャルだなんて
Don't say things like
言わないで
I'm just virtual.
あなたの音にまだ愛されていたい
I still want to be loved by your sound.
覚えていてね
Remember
わたしの声を
my voice.
あなたがくれた
All of this body
この身すべてを
that you gave me.
言の葉と
As words
初の音が交わる
and the first sounds intertwine,
この息と音とヒビカセ
this breath, sound, and echoing resonance.
あなたの生んだ音にただ恋をしていたの
I was simply in love with the sound you created.
悲しみ 怒り 宥心 すべて打ち鳴らす
Sorrow, anger, comfort—sounding them all out.
絶えず叫ぶ 声連ねる 余熱交ぜる 愛、絶艶めく
Screaming ceaselessly, linking voices, mixing heat, love allure.
魅了されていく
Becoming fascinated...
忘れないでね
Don't forget
わたしの声を
my voice.
画面越しでいい
Even through a screen,
ちゃんと愛して
love me properly.
ヴァーチャルだって
Just because I'm virtual,
突き放さないで
don't push me away.
あなたの音にまだ溺れていたい
I still want to drown in your sound.
覚えていてね
Remember
わたしの声を
my voice.
あなたがくれた
All of this body
この身すべてを
that you gave me.
見つめ合う
Gazing at each other,
あなたと二人
just the two of us,
重ねた息と音をヒビカセ
make our overlapped breath and sound resonate!
あなたの初音でこの声聴かせ
Let this voice be heard through your first sound,
オトヒビカセ
let the sound resonate!
はい！
Alright!
というわけで
So with that,
皆さん、新衣装になりました！
everyone, I have a new outfit!
どうですか？カッコ、カッコ、かっこいいですか？
How is it? Is it cool, cool, cool?
なんと今回は、ダンスを頑張ると決めたその時から決めていた...
This time, ever since I made up my mind to work hard on dancing...
ちょっとかっこいい系のダンス衣装になってみました！
I tried going with a cool-style dance outfit!
イエーイ！みんな写真いっぱい撮って撮って撮って撮って！
Yay! Everyone, take lots of photos, take them, take them!
イエーイ、カッコいいでしょう？
Yay, cool, right?
「可愛いばっかじゃん」「カッコいいはどこ行ったんだよ！」
"It's all just cute," "Where did cool go?!"
はい、というわけで新衣装になりました。
Right, so with that, this is my new outfit.
ゲストパートもね『絶対アイドル辞めないで』から
For the guest segment too, starting from "Zettai Idol Yamenai de",
あのソロになりまして『UNDEAD』『響かせと』続けてお送りさせていただきました！
going into solo "UNDEAD" and "Hibikaseto", we sent them back-to-back!
どうでしたか？
How was it?
めっちゃ頑張って、あの「足千切れそう」ってそういうことです。
I tried super hard, like "my legs feel like they're falling off".
本当にたくさん今回は、変身のために飛びました。足が千切れそうです。はい。
I really jumped around a lot for this transformation. My legs are about to tear off. Yes.
『絶対アイドル辞めないで』でもね、先輩方、そしてラプラスも来てくれて
In "Zettai Idol Yamenai de", my seniors and Laplus came as well,
ありがと... 激務だったね！本当に！
thank you... It was an intense schedule, wasn't it?! Truly!
本当に激務でしたね。皆さん一緒に頑張ってくださり、本当にありがとうございました！
It was really intense. Thank you all so much for working hard together with me!
そう！そしてですね、この後もまだまだゲストさんをたくさん呼んでおります！
Yes! And also, after this, we still have many more guests coming!
そしてござるも、実はこの...このカラーリングだけじゃないんですよ！
And actually Gozaru... isn't just about this coloring!
なので、そちらも公開していくので、みんなもお楽しみに！
So we'll be revealing that as well, look forward to it!
それでは次はゲストさんと一緒に歌わせていただきます！
Now then, next I will be singing together with a guest!
それでは、どうぞ！
Here you go!
ブラック★ロックシューター 何処へ行ったの？
Black Rock Shooter, where did you go?
聞こえますか？
Can you hear me?
ブラック★ロックシューター
[Song: Black Rock Shooter]
あとどれだけ叫べばいいのだろう
How much longer should I scream?
あとどれだけ泣けばいいのだろう
How many more tears should I shed?
もうやめて わたしはもう走れない
Enough already, I can't run anymore.
いつか夢見た世界が閉じる
The world I once dreamed of is closing.
真っ暗で明かりもない
It's pitch black, without a single light.
崩れかけたこの道で
On this crumbling path,
あるはずもないあの時の希望が見えた気がした
I felt as though I saw that hope from back then that shouldn't exist.
どうして
Why?
ブラック★ロックシューター 懐かしい記憶
Black Rock Shooter, nostalgic memories
ただ楽しかったあの頃を
Of those times when things were simply fun.
ブラック★ロックシューター でも動けないよ
Black Rock Shooter, but I can't move.
闇を駆ける星に願いを
A wish upon a star racing through the darkness,
もう一度だけ走るから
because I will run just one more time.
怖くて震える声でつぶやく
I whisper in a frightened, trembling voice,
わたしの名前を呼んで
"Call my name."
夜明けを抱く空
The sky embracing the dawn,
境界線までの距離
the distance to the horizon,
あともう一歩届かない
just one step more, yet out of reach.
こらえた涙があふれそうなの
The tears I suppressed seem about to overflow.
今下を向かないで
Don't look down now,
止まってしまう
or everything will come to a stop.
未来を生きていたいんだ
I want to live in the future,
わかったの
I understand now.
思い出して
Remembering it,
強く強く信じるの
I believe strongly, so strongly.
そうよ
That's right.
ブラック★ロックシューター 優しい匂い
Black Rock Shooter, a gentle scent.
痛いよ 辛いよ 飲み込む言葉
It hurts, it's painful, swallowing back these words.
どこへ行ったの？
Where did you go?
聞こえますか？
Can you hear me?
あとどれだけ叫べばいいのだろう
How much more should I shout?
あとどれだけ泣けばいいのだろう
How much more should I cry?
最初からわかっていた
I knew it from the beginning,
ここにいることを
that I was here.
わたしの中の
All the courage
全ての勇気が
inside of me
火をともして
lights the fire,
もう逃げないよ
and I won't run away anymore.
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter,
ひとりじゃないよ
you are not alone.
声をあげて
I don't mind even if
泣いたって構わない
you cry out loud.
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter,
見ていてくれる
you're watching over me.
いまから始まるの
My story
わたしの物語
is about to start now.
忘れそうになったら
If you seem to forget,
この歌を
I will sing
歌うの
this song.
Beyond the way
[Title: Beyond the way]
息つまるばかりで
I'm just suffocating,
ぬるい退屈な夜道で
on this lukewarm, dull street at night.
ルールは無視で行きたいね
I wanna go while ignoring the rules, right?
So burn my burn my heart
悟られそう
Feels like I'll be found out,
可か不可か Get down now
pass or fail, get down now.
あーあ もうきっと優等生ぶった "I" じゃ居られないくらい どうしようもない
Ah, I really can't stay acting like an honor student "I" anymore, there's no helping it.
yuh 無理目のクエスチョン
Yuh, an unreasonable question,
ha 実存？ フィクション？
Ha, real existence? Fiction?
You make me サゲなの何で？ I know the way
You bring me down, for what? I know the way.
願ってるばっかじゃ叶わない
It won't come true just by wishing.
めちゃくちゃにされたって変わらない
Nothing changes even if it gets messed up.
まあね
Oh well,
喰らい
eat this,
覚醒
awakening!
Find the way
待って ライトあびる感覚 甘い罠
Wait, this feeling of bathing in the light is a sweet trap.
見当違い dis も聞き飽きたわ
I'm sick of hearing misdirected dissing.
そりゃね 行けるところまで Take me higher
Well then, take me higher as far as I can go.
どう？ Turning back
How's that? Turning back?
無理ってとっくに分かってんでしょ
You've known for a long time that it's impossible, right?
悟られそう
Feels like I'll be found out,
可か不可 Get down now
pass or fail, get down now.
あーあ もうずっとしゃんと居られないや それは誰のせい？
Ah, I can't keep acting proper forever. Whose fault is that?
終わらない夢を描こう 描いて
Let's draw a never-ending dream, sketch it out,
願ったまま欲しがった その先へ
and go beyond what we wished and desired.
終わらない夜を超えていこう 超えていこう このまま
Let's cross over the never-ending night, keep crossing over like this,
焦がれた向こう側へ
to the other side we yearned for.
はあ ぶっちゃけ解せないや 勝算なくても行っちゃえ！とか
Hah, honestly I can't get it—like "Go for it even with no chance to win!"
運命感じる感受性は否定めない ウチら負けない
I can't deny the intuition of feeling fate. We won't lose!
飛べ 吠えろ 目で追って いつでも NO.1
Fly, bark, follow with your eyes, always No. 1!
そこどけ 速攻揺らせ 攻め 甘美な時 Ride on now
Move out of the way, shake 'em instantly, attack, ride on now in this sweet moment!
Shake it up まだまだ Go beyond the way, yuh
Shake it up, not done yet, go beyond the way, yuh!
息つまるばかりで ずるい言葉を探して
Just suffocating, searching for sneaky words,
(mellow mellow mellow)
I am me 研ぎ澄まし 本能に従って
I am me, hone yourself, follow your instincts,
行け Holla "We are the winners!"
and go! Holla, "We are the winners!"
So burn my burn my heart
Woah-oh-oh-oh
終わらない夢を描こう 描いて
Let's draw a never-ending dream, sketch it out,
願ったまま欲しがった その先へ
and go beyond what we wished and desired.
終わらない夜を超えていこう 超えていこう このまま
Let's cross over the never-ending night, keep crossing over like this,
焦がれた向こう側へ
to the other side we yearned for.
追いかけて合わせた背が熱くて
Chasing and standing back-to-back, the heat between us,
もう一生鳴り止まない 限界の向こう側へ
will never stop ringing for the rest of our lives, to the other side of limits!
How already steady
You got the way
はい！というわけで
Alright! So with that said,
本日はこのおふたりに来ていただきましたー！
we have these two guests joining us today!
イェーイ！
Yay!
初めてー！ありがとうございますー！
Our first time! Thank you so much!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
お誕生日おめでとうー！
Happy birthday!
ありがとうございますー！
Thank you so much!
お忙しいのに、おふたりとも今日はね
Even though you're both busy today,
っていうか、もうずっとレッスンからか...
or rather, ever since our lessons together...
本当にお付き合いいただきましてありがとうございます！
thank you so much for hanging out with me!
こちらこそありがとうございます！
Thank you as well!
今回はですね、誕生日で実は衣装が...
So for this birthday, actually my outfit...
短くて可愛い！見て見て！めちゃ可愛い！
It's short and cute! Look, look! So cute!
おへそ！おへそ見えてる！
Your navel! Your belly button is showing!
そう！やば！取られる！
Yeah! Oh no, it's gonna get stolen!
でも可愛い！ツインテール似合ってる！
But it's so cute! Twintails look great on you!
イェーイ！そうなんです！
Yay! That's right!
新しくね、ダンスする用みたいな衣装になったので
Since I got this new outfit made for dancing,
恐れ多くもおふたりを呼ぼうかな...
I wondered if I could dare invite you two...
ダンスが上手いおふたりを呼んでもいいのかなって言って、呼ばせていただきました！
wondering if it was okay to invite two great dancers, so I invited you!
ええー！私達ー？！
Eh?! Us?!
呼んでくれて... めっちゃ楽しかった！
Thanks for inviting us... It was so much fun!
レッスンもね、一緒に頑張っていただきまして...
And you worked hard with us during lessons too...
おふたりともめちゃくちゃ元が上手いから、風真ひとりだけ「どうしようかな」って...
Since you two are already so good, I was the only one worrying, 'What should I do...'
そんなことない！めっちゃ踊れてたよ！
That's not true! You danced super well!
最高なものが出来たと思います！
I think we created something amazing!
今頃コメントにはね、「めっちゃ良かったよ」が流れてると思います！
I bet the comments are full of 'It was so awesome!' right now!
めちゃくちゃ嬉しい！だって、いろはちゃんと初めてじゃん！
I'm so happy! Because this is our first time together, Iroha-chan!
一緒にダンスするの！こういうフォーメーションダンス！
Dancing together like this! A formation dance!
めっちゃできて嬉しい！
I'm so glad we got to do it!
いや嬉しい！本当に誘って良かったー！
I'm so happy! I'm really glad I invited you!
おふたりと一緒にね、この期間一緒に踊ってめちゃくちゃ勉強になりました、先生方！
Dancing with you both during this time was such a learning experience, teachers!
そんなことないですし！ありがとうございました！
Not at all! Thank you so much!
またね、何かあったらぜひ一緒に...
If another opportunity comes up, please let's...
ぜひやりましょう！私達も呼んでください！
Definitely! Let's do it! Call us again anytime!
じゃあ、この記念に、友情の証！強い、かっこいいポーズ、写真撮っとく... かっこいいポーズ！
So to mark the occasion, a symbol of friendship! A strong, cool pose for a photo... A cool pose!
かっこいいポーズが思いつかない！なんだー！
I can't think of a cool pose! What?!
可愛いー！めちゃ可愛い！まいっか！
So cute! Super cute! Oh well!
みんなたくさんSNSに投稿してくださいね！
Everyone, please post lots of photos on social media!
はい！と言いつつ、実はですね、もうひとつお願いがあって...
Alright! Having said that, actually, I have one more request...
今日この後、今日初お披露目のオリ曲があるんですけど...
Right after this, I have an original song premiering for the first time...
オリ曲ー？！やったー！楽しみ！どんな曲ー？
An original song?! Yay! Looking forward to it! What kind of song?
やっぱり風真いろは、かっこよくなりたくて、今回はかっこいい曲を持ってまいりました！
After all, Kazama Iroha wants to be cool, so I brought a really cool song this time!
イェーイ！楽しみー！
Yay! Can't wait!
可愛くてかっこいいおふたりから、やっぱちょっと勇気をもらってから行こうかなと...
I thought I'd draw some courage from the two of you who are both cute and cool...
かっこいいビーム！ビーム！うわー！
Cool beam! Beam! Woah!
すごい、なんか心強い... ちょっとイケメンになってきてる気がする。イケメンのポーズ...
Awesome, I feel so encouraged... I feel like I'm turning into a handsome guy. A handsome pose...
いいよ！かっこいいよ！
Looking good! Very cool!
いけてる気がする！いけてるー！いいよいいよ！
I feel like I'm nailing it! You're nailing it! Great, great!
よし！おふたりからめちゃくちゃエネルギーもらえたので、頑張ってきます！
Alright! I received so much energy from both of you, so I'll go give it my all!
おふたりとも今日はお祝いと、そして一緒に歌って踊ってくれて、応援ビームもありがとうございました！
Thank you both for celebrating, singing and dancing with me, and for the cheer beams!
こちらこそありがとうございました！また遊びましょうね！
Thank you so much as well! Let's hang out again!
はい！じゃあそれでは、この後新オリ曲を初お披露目させていただきます！それでは、せーの...
Yes! Well then, I will now premiere my new original song! Ready, set...
どうぞー！
Here it comes!
見た目だけじゃワカラナイ
You can't tell just from appearances
ワタシのこと可愛いだけど
You might just see me as cute, but
まさか思っていないよね？
surely you don't think that's all, right?
ワタシのホント知っていてほしい
I want you to know the real me
Passion Passion
Passion Passion Burning
Passion Passion Emotion
予測誤差の範囲と
Within the range of predictive error,
不測の事態も動じない
unforeseen situations won't shake me.
おすましフェイスでいるけど
I keep a calm expression,
心は常に青白く燃える
but my heart is always burning with a pale blue flame.
諦めはしない
I won't give up,
媚びたりもしない
I won't flatter,
ワタシを曲げない
I won't bend my true self.
扱いやすいヤツだと思うな
Don't think I'm easy to push around,
甘く見ると痛い目見るぞ
take me lightly and you'll pay the price.
それでもときには 逃げ出してしまいたい
Even so, sometimes I just want to run away.
そんな衝動に 弱音吐きたくなる真夜中もある
There are midnight moments when I want to give in to such impulses.
小さな小さな妥協が 積み重なり重なって動けない
Small, tiny compromises pile up until I can't move.
大きな大きな可能性 失くし 未来を狭めてしまうから
Because losing big, huge possibilities narrows down my future.
どんなに暗くても 辛くても 後悔だけはしない
No matter how dark or painful it gets, I won't have any regrets.
イケてるのは見た目じゃなくて 生きかたなんだ
Looking cool isn't about appearance, it's about how you live.
現実と理想との 距離を縮められたとしても
Even if I could close the gap between reality and my ideals,
おすましフェイスでいるだけ 何事もなかったかのように
I'll just keep a calm face, as if nothing happened at all.
立ち止まりはしない
I won't stand still,
後戻りもしない
I won't turn back,
夢を捨てない
I won't abandon my dreams.
可愛い見かけで らしいとからしくないとか 決めつけないで 全部がワタシ
Don't judge me by my cute look, or define what's like me or not—it's all me.
それでもときには 温もりが恋しい
Even so, sometimes I crave warmth.
そんな感情に 流されてしまいそうな真夜中もある
There are midnight moments when I feel like getting swept away by such feelings.
こんな甘い甘いことだけ 求めてしまうような 弱さいらない
I don't need the weakness of seeking only sweet, sweet things.
苦い苦い経験だって ワタシを強くしてくれるから
Because even bitter, bitter experiences make me stronger.
これがこれがワタシの ホントの真実
This is, this is my true reality.
とても狭い狭い世界の中だけで 終わらせたくはないんだ
I don't want to end things inside a very narrow, small world.
広い広い世界の果てまで 駆け抜けて生きていくんだから
Because I will run through to the ends of a vast, wide world and live on.
どんなに険しくて過酷でも 楽しんでやるさ
No matter how steep and harsh it is, I'll enjoy every bit of it.
イケてるのは見た目じゃなくて 生きかたなんだから
Because looking cool isn't about appearance, it's about how you live.
はい！ということで、皆さん！
Alright! So, everyone!
ゲストパートから続けて新オリ曲「ホントノワタシ」歌って踊らせていただきました！
Following the guest segment, I just sang and danced to my new original song, "Honto no Watashi"!
なんと風真いろは、7曲目のオリ曲です！
This is actually Kazama Iroha's 7th original song!
オリ曲のジャケットも届いているので見ていきましょう！こちらです！
The jacket art for the song is here, so let's check it out! Here it is!
はい！こちらの風真いろは新オリ曲7曲目「ホントノワタシ」は、
Yes! Kazama Iroha's 7th original song, "Honto no Watashi,"
こちら日付変わりまして19日0時よりリリースされることとなりました！
will be released tonight at midnight on the 19th!
今回の新衣装にちなんで、こちら作っていただきました！
It was made especially to match this new outfit!
ちょっと今までとだいぶ系統の違う曲になるんですけれども、
It's a quite different style from my previous songs, but...
あの、いつもみんなね、ありがたいことに風真いろはのこと「かっこいい」っていうよりは「かわいい」って言ってくださる方がいっぱいいるので、
well, everyone usually calls me "cute" rather than "cool," which I really appreciate...
「いや、かっこいいとこもあるんだよ」っていうのを伝えたくて作らせていただきました！
so I wanted to show that I have a cool side too!
こちら是非0時にリリースされたら、たくさん聴いて、またハッシュタグ「#みしていろはず」ので感想とか教えていただけたら嬉しいです！
Once it releases at midnight, please listen to it a lot and share your thoughts with the hashtag #みしていろはず!
そしてそして、ゲストパートについても話していきますかね。じゃあ戻って…
And next, let's talk about the guest segment as well! Let's switch back...
はい！ゲストでね、ミオ先輩と、そしてハジメちゃん、ベイ先輩と一緒に歌って踊らせていただきました！
Yes! As for our guests, I got to sing and dance with Mio-senpai, Hajime-chan, and Bae-senpai!
ミオ先輩、そしてベイ、そしてハジメちゃん、来てくれてありがとうー！
Mio-senpai, Bae, and Hajime-chan, thank you so much for coming!
もう本当に歌も難しかったし…
The song was really challenging, and...
ねぇねぇと始めちゃったやつに関しては
As for the part where we started with "hey hey,"
マジこれができなさすぎて
I really couldn't do this part,
一層やりすぎて
so I ended up overdoing it way too much...
あの 一生腰痛を抱えて
and carried back pain for a whole lifetime...
これ これが結構筋肉痛の原因でした
This was pretty much the main cause of my muscle soreness!
はい
Yes.
でも 一緒に歌って踊らせていただきまして
But being able to sing and dance together with you,
とってもとってもいい経験になりました！
it was such a wonderful experience!
皆さん、ありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you so much!
はい
Alright!
というわけで 次の曲に行く前に
So then, before moving on to the next song...
お水飲んでいいですか？
May I drink some water?
お水飲みます
I'm going to drink water.
お水
Water...
ロゴも見て 実は変わってた！
Look at the logo too, it actually changed!
よし
Alright.
お待たせしました
Thank you for waiting!
息整えて...
Catching my breath...
はい、次の曲なんですけれども
Yes, about the next song...
やっぱり
After all,
みんな「バラードも好きだよ」って言ってくれる方が多いので
so many of you tell me that you love ballads too,
今回の生誕LIVE
so for this Birthday Live,
バラード、やろうと思って持ってきました！
I brought a ballad that I wanted to perform!
はい
Yes.
ちょっとかっこいい感じに歌えるか
Whether I can sing it in a cool way,
いろいろ練習したんですけど
I practiced a lot...
ぜひ心を込めて歌うので
I'll sing it with all my heart,
聴いていただけると嬉しいです
so I'd be happy if you listen.
それでは 次の曲お聴きください
Now then, please listen to the next song...
W/X/Y
垂れ流したテレビの音
The sound of the TV playing in the background,
溜めてしまった洗濯物は今日こそ
today's the day to finally do the piled-up laundry.
晴れてもあえて外には出ないでいよう
Even if it's sunny, let's choose not to go outside.
映えないスナックとアルコールで乾杯をしよう
Let's toast with plain snacks and alcohol.
2人酸いも甘いも
The two of us, through sour and sweet times,
噛み合わないとしても
even if we don't always align,
お互い寄り添うように
so that we can lean into each other,
少しずらしてみようよ
let's shift ourselves just a little bit.
君がくれた太陽 月で隠れないよう
The sun you gave me, so it won't be hidden by the moon,
輝き弛まぬように歌うメロディ
a melody sung so that its sparkle never fades.
戯れる Slowly flowing day
Playfully, a slowly flowing day.
愛してるも通り越して
Going even beyond "I love you,"
似た者同士こうして
as two similar souls like this,
年老いるまでは笑っていたいね
I want us to keep smiling until we grow old.
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day.
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed.
In my dreams, fall asleep in bed.
起こすから morning call で
I'll wake you up with a morning call,
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
脱ぎっぱなしの足跡辿ると
Following the trail of discarded clothes,
不意をついて後ろから抱きつくの
taking you by surprise and hugging you from behind.
つい、繰り返すと忘れてしまいそうになるよ
When it keeps repeating, I almost start to forget,
振り返ると日々が当たり前じゃないこと
but looking back, these days are nothing to take for granted.
2人対の細胞
Our paired cells,
絡み合う特別を
this special closeness intertwined,
噛み締めて生きたいと思ったまどろみ抱く正午
wanting to cherish it as we live, holding onto this drowsiness at noon.
吐息、漏れた体温
Sighs, leaked body warmth,
微塵も逃さないよう
so that not even a trace slips away,
頭の中刻む甘いメモリー
sweet memories etched deep inside my head.
戯れる Slowly flowing day
Playfully, a slowly flowing day.
愛してるも通り越して
Going even beyond "I love you,"
違う者同士こうして
as two different souls like this,
年老いるまでは笑っていたいね
I want us to keep smiling until we grow old.
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day.
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed.
In my dreams, fall asleep in bed.
起こすから morning call で
I'll wake you up with a morning call,
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
重ねた手は離さないでいて
Hold onto my overlapping hand and don't let go,
ごめん、これそばに居たいだけだね
sorry, this is just me wanting to stay by your side.
抱えた想いはお互い様でしょ
The feelings we hold are mutual, right?
ほら、おあいこでしょ
See, we're even, aren't we?
すれ違い、間違いもあるし
There are misunderstandings and mistakes too,
筋書き通り行かない打診、悲しみだって
and unexpected turns or sadness that don't go as planned...
半分こにしよう
Let's share them half and half.
別れじゃない希望
A hope that isn't a farewell,
独りよがりにならないように、いつも
so that it never becomes selfish, always...
ありがとうを伝えたいのです
I want to convey my thanks.
これからは僕が支えてくって
I'll support you from now on,
呆れてしまうくらいにね
to the point where you might be amazed.
愛が増していく day by day
My love grows day by day.
面と向かうはどうしても
Whenever we face each other, somehow...
素直になれないな、ごめんね
I can't be honest, I'm sorry.
戯れる slowly flowing day
Playful, slowly flowing day.
愛してるも通り越して
Going far beyond "I love you,"
似た者同士こうして
like-minded people like this...
年老いるまで笑っていたいね
I want to laugh until we grow old.
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely lonely day.
夢の中 fall asleep in bed
In a dream, fall asleep in bed.
起こすから morning call で
I'll wake you with a morning call.
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
ありがとうございました
Thank you so much!
はい、それではですね
Alright then...
皆さん
Everyone...
ここまで聴いていただきまして
Thank you so much for listening
本当にありがとうございます
this far!
はい
Yes!
こんなにスタートさせていただいたんですけども
We've started off like this,
バラード、なかなか
but doing ballads...
3Dライブでやる機会がないので
I rarely get to do them in a 3D live,
すごく緊張しました
so I was really nervous!
どうだったでしょうか？
How was it?
あ、めっちゃ拍手とめっちゃいいっていうのが見える
Ah, I can see so many claps and 'so good' comments!
ありがとうございます
Thank you so much!
書籍、ここで皆さんお待ちかねの
And now, the moment you've all been waiting for...
あの告知を挟ませていただければと思います
I'd like to share an announcement!
それでは元気に行きます
Alright, let me do this with energy!
それでは、ドン！
Here we go, boom!
風真いろは 2025誕生日記念グッズ！
Kazama Iroha 2025 Birthday Commemorative Goods!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ビジュアルが大変よろしい！
The visuals look so great!
こちらのグッズが販売決定です！
These items are now officially on sale!
はい、というわけで詳細を見ていきましょう。ドン！
Alright, let me go over the details! Boom!
はい、まず1つ目は回転アクリルスタンド
First up is the Rotating Acrylic Stand!
イラストは Nardack 先生に書いていただきました！
The illustration was drawn by Nardack-sensei!
うわー！
Woah!
こちらですね、あの...ここです
So this one... right here...
裏表になってるっていう
It's double-sided!
カラーライズ衣装とこの新しい新衣装で裏表になってます
It features the Color Rise outfit and the new outfit on opposite sides.
くるくる回せるので
Since it spins around,
ござるのこと回して遊んでください。よろしくお願いします！
please spin Gozaru around and enjoy it! Thank you!
そして次がこちら！
And next is this!
はい、温感湯呑！
Yes, the Temperature-Sensitive Teacup!
これさっきサンプルが控室に届いて試しました
A sample just arrived in the green room earlier, so I tested it out!
あたたかいの入れると、ふわーってですね
When you pour something warm, it softly...
ちゃんとぽこべぇが浮き出て
Pokobea reveals itself!
リハやってる間に湯が冷め切ってちゃんと緑に戻っておりました
While doing rehearsals, the hot water cooled down and it turned back to green!
こちらもすごく可愛くて、お寿司屋さんとかにあるサイズなのかな？
This is also super cute! Is it like the size they have at sushi restaurants?
結構大きめのちゃんとした湯呑です。ぜひ使ってもらえたら嬉しいです！
It's quite a large, proper teacup. I'd be happy if you used it!
はい！そして次がこちら！
Alright! And next is this!
風真いろは ポップダンス衣装 ver.
Kazama Iroha Pop Dance Outfit ver...
の、ぬいぐるみです！
...Plushie!
ぜひお出迎えしてほしいな！
I really hope you welcome it home!
ござるさんのぬいぐるみでみんな遊んでくれー！
Everyone, please play with Gozaru's plushie!
ということでツインテールの新衣装がなんとぬいぐるみになりました！
So the new twintail outfit has actually been made into a plushie!
手持ちじゃなくて、こう...こういうタイプだと思うので
It's not a handheld strap type, but this sitting type, I think,
ぜひみんなのお家に飾ってもらえたら嬉しいです！
so I'd love it if you display it in your home!
そして、次はこちら！
And next is this!
なんとござるのこれ！これとおそろいのこれがでます！
Look, Gozaru's this! A matching version of this is coming out!
ちょっと待って、もう一回やり直していい？
Wait a second, can I redo that?
これとおそろいのネックレスが出ます！
A necklace matching this is coming out!
普段ね、アクセサリーとか付けない、体質的に付けないよーって方も
Even for those who usually don't wear accessories,
まあ良かったらこちらね
if you'd like,
さっきのぬいぐるみにつけて一緒にセットにして飾っていただいたり
you can tie it on the plushie to display together,
イベントのときに付けて来てもらえたら嬉しいです。おしゃれです！
or wear it to events! It's stylish!
ござるのとお揃いに良かったらしましょう！
Let's match with Gozaru if you like!
というわけで、フルセットがこんな感じ！
So, here is what the full set looks like!
うわー！なんだか爽やかですね！
Wow! It feels so refreshing!
ライブタイトルの通り Reversible なんでね、色々反転反転が付いてたりします
True to the live title 'Reversible', there are various inverted themes!
そして！購入特典はこちら！
And here is the full set purchase bonus!
「この戦争を終わらせに来ました」
"I have come to end this war."
今回はですね、グッズが2種類出るということで数量限定はせずに
This time, since two outfit versions of merch are releasing,
ちょっと変わった特典にしてみました！
without limiting quantity, we made a slightly unique bonus!
こちらは裏表のタロットカードが付いてきます！
It comes with a double-sided tarot card!
片面にはね、風真の複製サインとメッセージが入っております
One side includes Kazama's printed autograph and message.
こちらもね、こう裏表で...
This one is also double-sided...
楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいです
I hope you'll enjoy it!
数量限定とかではないので、ゆっくりね、購入していただければと思います
Since it's not a limited quantity release, please feel free to take your time purchasing.
販売開始時間がこの後21時なんですけど
Sales were scheduled to start after this at 21:00, but...
ちょっと生配信の関係上、ちょっと生配信伸びる可能性のほうが今大なので、生配信中に
...since this live stream is likely to run overtime, during the stream...
皆さん、あの、カート見に行ってください
...please go check out your shopping cart!
あ、でも数量限定とか無いので、安心してください
Ah, but again, it's not limited quantity, so don't worry.
はい、そしてフルセットの特典もう1つあります。こちらです。
Yes, and there's one more perk for the full set! Here it is.
はい！みんな大好きホロカのカードが1枚ついてきまーす！
Yes! It comes with one Hololive Official Card Game card that everyone loves!
はい、皆さん良かったらお手にとって、ホロカ勢の皆さんは使ってくださいね
So if you like, please get one, and for those playing Holoca, please use it!
遊び方とか、あとカードの詳細は、hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAMEの公式ホームページにてご確認ください！
For how to play and further details on the cards, please check the official Hololive Official Card Game website!
よし！今台本めっちゃ見た！言えなかったらやばいと思って。
All right! I looked at my script so hard just now, thinking I'd be in trouble if I messed up.
そして、こちら一緒にこの入れさせていただくカードは日本語版のみとなっておりますので、ご容赦ください。
Also, please note that the card included in this set will only be available in Japanese.
はい！カートのオープンですが、こちらですね
Okay! As for opening the cart, it's right here.
100万人記念グッズと誕生日記念グッズ、両方同時なので、皆さんよろしくお願いします
The 1-million subscriber merch and birthday merch are opening at the same time, so please check them out!
ちょっと、ごめんなさい！生配信押しゃってごめんね！ホロメンも、ホロメンも配信押してすみません！
Ah, sorry about that! Sorry for the stream running long! Holo-members, sorry for pushing back your streams too!
はい！というわけで、ちょっとお水飲みます。
Okay! With that said, I'm going to drink some water.
はい！というわけで
All right! So then...
あと最後のお知らせといたしまして
As for the final announcement...
この後本編終了次第、ちょっとまた時間がね、確定、15分からか20分からかどっちかになると思うんですけど
Right after this main stream ends—though the exact start time is still TBD, either in 15 or 20 minutes...
風真いろはのメンバーシップ限定のアンコール配信がございますので
...there will be an encore stream exclusive to Kazama Iroha channel members!
みんなが見たかったあの曲やこの曲を歌ったり踊ったりしますので、良かったら見に来てください
I'll be singing and dancing to songs you've all been wanting to see, so please come watch!
よろしくお願いします。メンバーシップギフトとか今日から入ってくださった隊員さんもありがとうございます！
Thank you so much! Also, thanks to everyone who gifted memberships or joined as Corps members today!
はい、そしてなんと残念なことに、次の曲が皆さん、このライブ最後の曲となります
And now, sadly, the next song will be the final song of this live concert.
えー皆さん、もう最後は何を歌うかある程度予想されている方も多いかと思いますが
I'm sure many of you have already guessed what the final song will be, but...
改めまして、この度は風真いろは生誕ライブ2025お越しくださいまして、本当にありがとうございました！
Once again, thank you so much for coming to Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2025!
そしてあの、制作のために一生懸命頑張ってくださったスタッフさんやダンサーの先生やマネージャーさんや皆さん、本当にクリエイターの皆さんもありがとうございました！
And to the staff who worked so hard to produce this, the dance teachers, managers, and all creators—thank you so much!
あの正直いろいろあった、昨年の年末から
Honestly, a lot has happened since late last year...
ここまで声が戻ってライブができるっていうことがほぼ奇跡
For my voice to recover enough to hold a live concert like this feels almost like a miracle.
なんだったら、もう半分諦めかけていたんですけども
Honestly, I had almost half given up hope, but...
スタッフの皆さんやファンの隊員さんたちがすごい支えてくださって、いろんな方に支えられて本日実施することができました。本当にありがとうございます！
Thanks to the overwhelming support from staff and all my Corps fans, I was able to hold this live today. Thank you so much!
正直まだまだ本調子じゃない部分が多いのは正直なところです
To be completely honest, there are still many areas where I'm not back at 100%.
だけど、今日少しでもこのライブを見てたくさんの人に元気が、1人でも多く届いていればなと思っております
But I hope watching this live today brings energy to as many of you as possible.
これからもリハビリしながらですが、精一杯頑張ってまいりますので、皆さんこれからもよろしくお願いします！
I'll continue working hard while doing rehabilitation, so please keep supporting me going forward!
はい、というわけで
Alright then!
最後の曲にふさわしいこの曲、皆さん最後に聞いてください
Please listen to this final song, perfectly fitting for the end...
風真いろは新オリジナル曲『君にしか読めない手紙』
Kazama Iroha's new original song: "A Letter Only You Can Read."
「ありがとう」書くとしたら 毎日になっちゃうくらい
If I were to write "Thank you", it would fill up every single day
重すぎる私の想いは 最後に伝えるね
These feelings of mine are too heavy, so I'll tell you at the very end
『君にしか読めない手紙』
"A Letter Only You Can Read"
拝啓 私を形作った君へ
Dear you, who shaped who I am
相変わらず言葉を 届け続けています
As always, I continue to send my words to you
拝啓 未来で私待ってる君へ
Dear you, waiting for me in the future
響く音に愛など なく過ごすでしょうか
Will you spend your days without love in the echoing sound?
不安が無い日なんて たぶん無かったけど
There probably wasn't a single day without anxiety, but...
私の言葉 君の言葉 重なって笑えたんだ
Our words overlapped, and we were able to smile
「ありがとう」書くとしたら 毎日になっちゃうくらい
If I were to write "Thank you", it would fill up every single day
私の想いは
My feelings...
最後に伝えるね
I'll tell you at the very end.
君がいる それだけでさ 理由になるなんて
Just having you here becomes my reason to go on—
奇跡
it's a miracle.
ありがとう 足りないの 誤魔化すよ
"Thank you" isn't enough, so I try to gloss over it...
愛してる
I love you.
魔法石のブレスレット
A bracelet made of magic stones,
シロツメクサの女王様
the queen of white clovers...
プラスチックだらけの宝石箱で
In a jewelry box full of plastic,
ずっと遊べるよ 君と
I could play with you forever.
思い出の片たち
The pieces of our memories
溢れるこの場所で
overflow in this place.
私の言葉 君の言葉 重ねて
Joining my words with your words,
笑ってたい
I want to keep smiling.
忘れられる世界で今
In a world where things get forgotten,
私を選んだ生き方
this is the way of life I chose.
手紙をさ 書いたからさ
Because I wrote a letter,
この音に乗せて
set to this melody...
ありがとう 書くとしたら 毎日になっちゃうくらい
If I wrote down "thank you," it'd become an everyday thing...
重すぎる私の想いは
My feelings, which are far too heavy,
最後に伝えるね
I'll tell you at the very end.
君がいる それだけでさ 理由になるなんて
Just having you here becomes my reason to go on—
奇跡
it's a miracle.
ありがとう 足りないの 誤魔化すよ
"Thank you" isn't enough, so I try to gloss over it...
愛してる
I love you.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
風真いろは 100万人記念 「君にしか読めない手紙」 7月1日 MV公開
[Kazama Iroha 1 Million Subscribers Commemoration: "A Letter Only You Can Read" MV Release on July 1st]